# Yves-Marie Plard

ymplard@gmail.com - yvesmarieplard.fr

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Experienced French engineer with 6+ years in Power, Software & Healthcare industries. Strong interest in data analysis.

\* Healthcare & Power Industry \* Software Development \* Python \* Databases \* Project Management \* Agile Methodology \* Digitalization \*

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### 4D - Database Management System & IDE

Jul 2021- Present

Professional Services Team - Project manager

San Jose, USA

- Led teams of 3+ developers in the end-to-end execution of software projects, ensuring top-down oversight at every stage.
- Successfully managed multiple concurrent projects (10+ software developments per year).
- Conducted client meetings, including high-level executives, to discuss project progress and requirements.

#### General Electric - GE Healthcare

Sept. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Women Health Imaging Service Team - Responsible for digitalization transformation

Paris, France

- Developed predictive maintenance models in Python, saving costs & unplanned downtime. Engineered rules for automated alerts before a failure occurs on a machine (20k\$/year/rule saved).
- Lead projects for monitoring new machines logs as part of the company data strategy, supporting databases development (Oracle, Greenplum, MySQL) using Spoon & Logstash.
- Created automated tools for maintenance costs calculation (based on Natural Language Processing models)
- Lead a team of 3 to develop a **new feature for a service platform** (500+ hospitals using the feature)

### General Electric - GE Power

Sept. 2017 - Sept. 2019

Belfort – Paris, France

**EEDP – Edison Engineering Development Program** 

Two-year early career program consisting of four rotational assignments. Combining advanced engineering coursework (10+ hours/week) with valuable work experience.

- 1. Systems Team: Led a team of 2 to define a comprehensive maintenance program for accessories of a 1600MW nuclear power plant.
- 2. **BoP Nuclear Team**: Quantified degradations in heat exchangers of nuclear power plants, identifying and addressing a 14MW loss (equivalent to \$4.4 million annually).
- 3. **Testing Team**: Conducted performance tests on a 650MW gas turbine and spearheaded a 10+ person team to install instrumentation.
- 4. New Product Introduction Team: Developed a 1D model for the gas injection system of a 120MW power station.

## AREVA - Nuclear Power & Renewable Energy Multinational Company

Mar. - Sept. 2017

Intern - Configuration Team

Paris, France

• Structured the database containing technical modifications inherited from the Flamanville Nuclear Power Plant.

### EDUCATION

### SHANGHAI JIAO TONG UNIVERSITY

2015-2017

## **DUAL DEGREE - MATERIALS SCIENCE & ENGINEERING**

Shanghai, China

Relevant coursework: Industrial Engineering, Operational Research. Master's thesis focused on characterizing a
material primarily applied within the aerospace industry.

## ARTS ET METIERS PARISTECH

2013-2015

## GRANDE ÉCOLES D'INGÉNIEURS – ENGINEERING SCHOOL(BA AND MS)

Lille, France

• Relevant coursework: Optimization, Mathematics & Physics, Industrial Engineering, Operational Research, Mechanical Design & Simulation, Programming (Python, Matlab).

#### YCÉE LIVET

2011-2013

## PREPARATORY CLASS - PHYSICS, MATHEMATICS & INDUSTRIAL SCIENCES

Nantes, France

• Two-year intensive preparation for admission to French Engineering Grandes Écoles. Graduated with honors.

#### LANGUAGE & SKILLS

- French: Native | English: Fluent | Chinese: Intermediate level
- Computer Skills: Python (Intermediate level), SQL (Prior experience), JavaScript (Prior experience).

## **ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS**

- **Hobbies:** Sailing & fishing. Chess.
- Sports: Squash & tennis enthusiast, Competitive runner (Tiberias Marathon Jan. 2020, Paris Half-Marathon March. 2019)